- 让开-小心
- Move aside. - Careful.
帮我看看5540809号
Please check no. 5540809.
在哪里呢…
Hello. 5547829...
通过了吗？
Did we clear?
我们俩都没过吗？
Both of us?
晚上才上课，继续睡吧
The class is in the evening. Go off to sleep.
海莉娅
Dhairya.
我刚刚做了一个梦
I just saw a dream.
我在梦里吗？
Was I a part of it?
是的
Yes.
那一定是个美梦
Then it must be a good one.
是的，很美的梦
Yes, it was a good one.
你没注意到吗？
Didn't you notice?
我没有注意到什么？
What is it that I did not notice?
海莉娅送给他的那副眼镜
The spectacles that Dhairya had gifted him.
- 所以呢?-所以呢？
- So? - So?
他现在还戴着
He still has it with him.
眼镜当然很耐用
The spectacles must be durable.
又没坏，所以他一直戴着有什么大不了的？
They did not break so he has kept it. What is the big deal in this?
7年? 有人一副眼镜戴7年吗？
7 years? Does anyone keep spectacles for 7 years?
甘地的眼镜仍然保存在博物馆里，状况良好
Gandhiji's spectacles are still kept in the museum in good condition.
那甘地的眼镜盒还在吗？
Is the case of Gandhiji's spectacles still there?
但他一直保管得很好
But he has kept it safely.
就是海丽娅在上面划掉品牌标签，写下了她名字的眼镜盒
The one on which Dhairya had cut Dahiya and wrote her name.
你不认识他吗? 他是个吝啬鬼
Don't you know him? He is a miser.
他过去备考的时候在电视的巨响中学习
He used to study in the loud sound of TV
却没有花钱去换房间
but did not spend more money and changed the room.
除非眼睛坏了，否则他不会扔掉的
Till it is not broken he wouldn't throw it.
你没理解我的意思
You are not trying to understand.
看着他的眼睛
Just look into his eyes.
你看的是眼镜又不是眼睛
Even you look at the eyes and not at the spectacles.
看着他的眼睛！
Look into his eyes!
我现在很困惑，SK
I have a doubt, SK.
你为什么要把问题复杂化，兄弟？
Why are you complicating things, brother?
他在你面前接受了你们的关系
He accepted your relationship in front of you.
他为你感到高兴，你为什么不能接受这一点呢？
He is happy for you and why are you not able to digest that?
海莉娅是他的过去，所以忘了吧
Dhairya was his past so forget about that.
不要反应过度，明白吗？
Don't overreact. Understood?
拉上拉链
Zip it up.
拉链没开
It is zipped.
他去哪儿了？
Where did sir go?
先生付完帐就走了
Sir left after paying the bill.
醒醒，水在哪里？
Wake up SK. Where is water?
呼吸，SK 呼吸
Pema! Breathe, SK breathe.
- 深呼吸-要带他去看医生吗？
- SK breathe. - Shall we take him to the doctor?
不，不需要
No. That is not needed.
- SK-SK.
- SK. - SK.
发生了什么？
What happened?
我可能是焦虑症发作了
I think it is an anxiety attack.
在预考前的一周，许多人都得了这种病
A week before the prelims many people have it.
一定发生了什么事
Something must have happened.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
你什么时候开始焦虑了？
Since when have you started getting anxiety attacks?
这种事经常发生在我身上
It usually happens to me.
我父亲打电话给我
My father had called me.
他又问了同样的问题，如果考不过怎么办
He was asking the same question that what you will do if you do not clear.
然后呢？
Then?
你每次都跟他说什么？
What do you tell him every time?
每次我都假装生气
Every time I pretend to be angry.
说为什么要认为我会考不过
Saying why should I think that I will not clear.
那么这次又发生了什么？
Then what happened this time?
他让我好好想想
He asked me to think.
这是最后一次机会了
This is the last attempt
如果我考不过，我就不得不做点什么
and I will have to do something if I do not clear.
我没有任何备选方案
I do not have any Plan B.
如果你考不过还好，你还有一份工作
If you do not clear it is fine as you have a job
他父亲有一家工厂，那我呢？
and his father has a factory. What about me?
有备选方案是很重要的
It is very important to have Plan B.
你寄出道德规范说明了吗？
Have you mailed the ethics notes?
你现在又怎么了？
Now, what has happened to you?
普拉加蒂已经通过了 PCS考试
Pragati has cleared PCS.
她什么时候报名了 PCS？
When did she give PCS?
这是她的备选方案
This was her Plan B.
她现在已经脱离危险了-那 UPSC 呢？
She is leaving now that she has cleared. - And UPSC?
毕竟这份工作也是公务员
After all the job is that of a civil servant
所以她对现状很满意
so she got satisfied with less.
这对她有好处
Good for her.
她开始无视我了
She has started ignoring me.
实际上，她很不成熟
As it is she is very immature.
- 那天在茶摊...-她没那么幼稚
- The other day at the tea stall... - She is not that immature.
她也知道在纳加尔产生的感情应该留在这里
Even she knows that relationships of Rajinder Nagar stay back here.
你应该告诉叔叔的
You should have told uncle
在预考结束之后再订婚
to keep engagement after the prelims.
我不能回去了
I will not be able to come.
这不可能
This cannot happen.
我一会儿打电话给你，我得走了，再见
I shall call later and talk to you. I have to leave. Bye.
对不起，邮件什么时候发来的？
Sorry. When did the mail come?
第一封邮件是一周前发来的
The first mail came a week ago.
你不是休了一年假吗？
Wasn't your sabbatical for a year?
是的
Yes.
但现在还不到六个月
But it has hardly been six months now.
他们说有一个重要的项目出现了
They are saying that an important project has come up.
他们要求我下周就回去上班，否则就辞职
They are asking me to join next week or resign.
我觉得尼禄的订婚也是个大问题
And I was feeling that Neelu's engagement was a big problem.
现在怎么办？
Now what?
你的 b 计划是什么？
What is your Plan B?
我的 a 计划是通过 UPSC考试
Look my Plan A is to clear UPSC,
成为一名公务员
become a civil servant
这样我就可以根除毒品，特别是在农村地区
so that I can work on eradicating drugs especially in rural areas.
我的 b 计划就是没有通过 UPSC 的情况下
My Plan B is to work in rural areas to eradicate drugs
在农村地区铲除毒品
without clearing UPSC.
哇！
Wow!
你制定了一个完整的计划
You have made a full-proof plan.
真是个天才
What a genius?
上帝给了我一个敏锐的头脑，所以制定计划很容易
God has given me a sharp mind so it becomes easy.
很容易是因为这是你的第二次考试，而不是最后一次
It becomes easy because it is your second attempt and not the last.
你觉得怎么样? 我现在该怎么办？
What do you think? What should I do now?
你应该自己做这个决定
You should be making this decision yourself.
如果我接受这份工作
If I join the job
那么这个决定也会影响你，对吗？
then it will impact you too. Right?
我希望
I hope.
阿比拉什，这应该是你的决定，而且只是你的决定
Abhilash, this should be your decision and only your decision.
这个考试竞争很激烈
This exam is so competitive
一个错误的决定会带来沉重的代价
that a wrong decision can cost heavily.
BSNL 已经推出了远程包
BSNL has come up with long-distance packs.
非常便宜
It is very cheap.
如果需要的话，我可以负担得起
And if need arises I can afford it.
先生，我还有一半的休假时间
Sir, half of my sabbatical still remains.
- 如果可以的话我想延长假期-我不能这样做，阿比拉什
- If you wish you can extend it. - I cannot do that, Abhilash.
你有良好的记录，所以你才有机会回来
You had a good record so that is why you are getting a chance.
公司已有30多名员工被解雇
More than 30 employees have been laid off from the company.
我明白，先生
I understand sir.
如果你愿意，你可以延长几个月
If you wish you can extend for few months.
我只是需要延期几个月..
I just need the extension for few months...
阿比拉什，你很清楚你最后一次考试的结果
Abhilash, you very well know the result of your last attempt.
你认为成为一个 IPS 很容易吗？
Do you think it is so easy to become an IPS?
IAS 先生，我想成为IAS
IAS sir. I want to become an IAS.
这次我非常有信心
And this time I am very confident.
那你为什么还要浪费彼此的时间？
Then why are you wasting yours as well as my time?
如果你百分之百确定，阿比拉什
If you were 100% sure Abhilash
那你在离开之前就该辞职了
then you would have resigned before leaving
也不会休假
and would not have taken a sabbatical.
这个周末前告诉我结果
Let me know by this weekend otherwise,
否则你会收到你的解雇信
you will receive your termination letter.
你现在满意了吗？
Are you satisfied now?
你现在开心了吗？
Are you happy now?
他的一生永远不会改变
He will never change in life.
他不在的时候你为什么大喊大叫？
Why are you now shouting when he is not around?
你应该当着他的面骂他
You should have cursed in front of him.
我在骂你
I am cursing you.
我只是在尝试，我的意图没有错
I was just trying. My intent was not wrong.
我要生气了，混蛋
I am getting angry, motherfucker.
格里，对不起，我道歉
Guri, I am sorry. I apologize.
得了吧
Forget it.
他甚至连告别都没有，就这样走了
He did not even think it right to talk. He just left.
这证明了什么
This proves that
有才华的人不能治理我们的国家
deserving people are not running our country.
而是一些像他这样的混蛋统治着我们
There are certain fuckers like him who are ruling us.
如果他不来参加我的婚礼，我也不介意
It does not bother me if he does not come to attend my wedding.
你想在婚礼上和他跳舞所以现在就跳吧..
You wanted to dance with him at the wedding. So dance now...
现在跳舞吧..
So dance now...
结束了，兄弟，我为此道歉
It is over, buddy. I apologized for that.
如果他小气，那你也小气
If he is cheap then so are you.
在过去的六年里，他没有来见过你
He did not come to meet you in the last six years
好像你每天都在给我打电话似的
and as if you were calling me every day.
就在你婚礼的前10天你才出现
Just 10 days before you are telling about your wedding
他什么也没说就走了
and he left without saying anything.
你们俩都很自私，那我呢？
You both are selfish. What about me?
是不是正在上映《茶花女》的一个场景? 我是赛义夫 · 阿里 · 汗吗？
Is a scene of Dil Chahata movie is going on? Am I Saif Ali Khan?
你们两个都是懦夫，你们两个都不敢面对事实
You both are cowards. You both cannot face the truth.
坐在后面
Sit Behind.
- 古丽，骑慢点-安静地坐着
- Guri, ride slowly. - Sit quietly.
格里，我们走那条路
Guri, we had to go that way.
- 你走错路了-安静地坐着
- You are going on the wrong way. - Keep sitting quietly.
发生了什么？
What happened?
你是否觉得你来参加 UPSC 考试的决定是错误的？
Do you feel your decision to write the UPSC exam was wrong?
上周你去哪了？
Where were you for the last one week?
我回家了
I had gone home.
我希望一切都好? 有什么急事吗？
I hope everything is fine? Was there an emergency?
是的，差不多是这样
Yes, something like that.
你得到了这么多嫁妆吗？
Were you getting so much dowry?
至少可以等到预备考试
You could have at least waited till prelims.
爱情婚姻？
Love marriage?
我曾经在一所公立学校教书
I used to teach in a government school.
那是我第一次见到库苏姆
That was then when I met Kusum for the first time.
当我们进一步发展我们的关系时，我们的家人也同意了
When we took our relationship further then our families also agreed.
我觉得库苏姆和我应该得到更好的
I felt that Kusum and I deserve something better.
我告诉她我的梦想是成为一名 IAS
I told her about my dream of becoming an IAS.
她支持我
She supported me
但她的家人不同意
but not her family.
我请求他们给我一年的时间
I had requested them to give me one year
现在已经四年了
and today it has been four years.
那库苏姆呢？
What about Kusum?
她已经等我四年了
She has been waiting since last four years.
她为了我唯一的梦想牺牲了她所有的梦想
She sacrificed all her dreams for my single dream.
她还能阻止她的家人做什么呢？
How much more could she stop her family members?
桑迪普兄弟，你对这次订婚不满意吗？
Brother Sandeep, aren't you happy with this engagement?
事实并非如此
That is not the case.
桑迪普，这次你一定会成功的
This time you will surely clear, Sandeep.
不仅我，而且每个人都是这么想的，这次你一定能考上
Not only I but everyone thinks the same. You will surely clear this time.
去年我只差一名被排除在名单之外
Last year I was out of the list for just one number.
一个名次浪费了我整整一年的时间
Just one number wasted my one entire year.
库苏姆有四年这样的负担
Kusum has a burden of four such years.
问题出在哪
What is the problem
如果戴上这枚戒指，她的负担就会减轻？
if by wearing this ring her burden gets less?
但另一个问题就会随着这枚戒指的出现而产生
But another question arises with this ring.
如果今年没考上，我该怎么办？
What will I do if I don't clear this year?
以前是别人问我
Earlier people used to ask me
现在我问自己
and now I am asking myself.
如果今年没考上，我该怎么办？
What will I do if I don't clear this year?
桑迪普，你有没有想过
Sandeep, didn't you ever think that
如果你加入培训计划，你会表现得更好吗？
you would have performed better if you would join some coaching?
我的意思是你会得到一些帮助
I mean you would have got some help.
我肯定会从中获益
I would have surely got some help.
该怎么说呢？
What to tell you?
我的经济状况不好
My financial condition is not good.
我应该考虑家里的食物还是培训课程？
Should I think about the food at home or about coaching?
我的条件就是这样
This is my condition.
有很多债务
There's a lot of debt
我的家人确实相信
My family does believe
我今年能考上
that I will clear this year.
他们强迫我参加培训课程
They forced me to join the coaching.
但是我让他们相信我不需要辅导
But I made them believe that I don't need coaching.
我拒绝了
I refused it.
我不能以他们的食物为代价而参加培训
Now I will not be able to join coaching at the cost of their food.
我能做吗？
Can I do it?
这就是我今年没有加入的原因
That is why I did not join this year.
桑迪普，你有什么 b 计划吗？
Sandeep, do you have any Plan B?
B 计划是为失败者准备的
Plan B is for losers.
明白吗？
Understood?
我曾经以为 b 计划是为失败者准备的
I used to think that Plan B is for losers
所以我才辞去了政府的工作
and that is why left my government job.
现在我明白了
Now I have understood
B 计划到底是什么
what Plan B means.
尊敬的领导：我想……
很好，佩玛
Very good, Pema.
- 你觉得怎么样?-很不错
- How did you like it? - Very nice.
格里
Guri.
对不起，我没有听到最后一部分，我走神了
Sorry, I did not hear the last part. I was lost.
格里迷失在普拉加蒂
Nowadays Guri is lost in Pragati.
格里，我觉得你的行为不对
Guri, I don't feel your behavior is right.
我告诉你，他看起来就像阿文 · 塞缪尔
I am telling you he seems to be like Arvind Samuel.
这个阿文 · 塞缪尔是谁？
Who is this Arvind Samuel?
你没听说过阿文 · 塞缪尔的传说故事吗？
Haven't you heard about Arvind Samuel's legend story?
- 你没告诉他吗 SK?-你告诉他这个故事
- Didn't you tell him, SK? - You tell him the story.
- 告诉我-他在说
- Tell me. - He is telling.
阿文 · 塞缪尔是个有抱负的人，他是个聪明人
Arvind Samuel was one of the aspirants. He was a smart guy.
第一年，他开始了一段感情
In the first year, he got into a relationship.
他们开始同居关系
They had a live-in relationship.
他的女朋友通过了 UPSC，但是阿文没有通过
His girlfriend cleared UPSC but Arvind did not.
第二段关系也是如此
Same with the second relationship.
新女友，新同居者，但结果都是一样的
New girlfriend, new live-in but the result was the same.
女朋友通过了 UPSC，而他没有
She cleared UPSC and he did not.
第三年也发生了同样的事情
The same happened in the third year.
三年三个女朋友都通过了考试
Three years, three girlfriends, and all of them cleared.
但是阿文一直没通过
But Arvind did not clear.
去年，阿文德经常让大家坐在这里
In the last year, Arvind used to make everyone sit here
做了一个关于 UPSC 和爱的讲座
and give a lecture on UPSC and love.
他以回答的形式介绍
He used to give intro in answer form,
结构和流程图，并得出结论
structure, and flow chart and reached a conclusion that
纳加尔是不存在爱情的
relationships of Old Rajinder Nagar never work.
对的
It is right.
如果女朋友通过，那么男朋友就不能通过
If the girlfriend clears then boyfriend does not.
如果男朋友通过了，女朋友就不会
And if the boyfriend clears then girlfriend does not.
如果碰巧两者都通过了，那么一个是 IAS，另一个是 IFS
And if by chance both clear then one is IAS and other one is IFS
如果两者恰好都是IAS，那么他们就是不同的部门
and if by chance both are IAS their cadres are different.
在这里建立的情感关系永远不会长久
Relationships that are made here are never successful.
你还记得那天我说我做了个梦吗？
Do you remember I had told you about my dream?
记得
Yes.
我梦到…
I dreamt that
我们都是
we both
预备考试不及格
failed in the prelims.
我还以为是个美梦
I thought it was a happy dream.
是美梦
It was.
这件事让我…
This thing is making me
从那天开始就心烦意乱
upset since that day.
我不明白
I did not understand.
小时候，你看《猫和老鼠》的时候更倾向谁？
Dhairya, in childhood, whom did you support while watching Tom and Jerry?
杰瑞
Jerry.
-杰瑞-好的
Jerry. Okay.
我也是
Me too.
我想每个人都会倾向杰瑞
I think everybody did.
你知道为什么杰瑞每次都赢吗
Do you know why did Jerry win every time
而汤姆每次都输？
and Tom lost every time?
因为汤姆不是为了食物
Because Tom was fighting for food for just one time.
而杰瑞在为自己的生存而战
But jerry was fighting for his survival.
没有 b 计划
There was no Plan B for
你拒绝了你的老板吗？
Did you refuse to your boss?
但后来我意识到..
But then I realized...
那天我在梦里很不开心
I was not happy in my dream the other day
因为我还有工作
because I still had a job.
即使这样我仍然觉得那是个美梦，因为…
I was happy because
你还在我身边
I still had you.
海莉娅，每个有野心的人都知道
Dhairya, every aspirant knows that
我们之间的关系
the relationships made
在这个地方
in Rajendra Nagar
是不会长久的
are not forever.
你知道..
You know...
所以..
So...
所以我们能在一起的唯一方法就是
So the only way we can stay together is that
我们都没通过 UPSC
we both fail the UPSC.
你真的认为我是你的 b 计划吗？
Do you really think I am your Plan B?
我不知道
I don't know.
我能确定的只有
All I know is that going to
23天后的考试大厅
the examination hall after 23 days
想明白这些对我来说很痛苦
would be difficult for me knowing that
通过考试最终还是会失去你
passing the exam would be eventually losing you.
你是对的
You were right
对这个决定1%的怀疑，都会让我付出沉重的代价
that 1% doubt on this decision can cost me heavily.
你认为你所做的是正确的吗？
Do you think whatever you are doing is right?
我不知道这是对还是错
I don't know whether it is right or wrong
但我觉得这是必要的
but feel this is necessary.
“我希望我们能在一起”
"I wanted us to be together."
“你想成为我的一部分”
"You wanted to be a part of me."
“那是什么样的承诺?”
"What kind of promise was that?"
“这种团结是怎么破灭的?”
"How did this togetherness got shattered?"
“以前我和你在一起过，现在我不在了”
"I was with you sometime back and now I am not."
”我不会回去”
"I shall not go back"
“我的眼睛很沉重... ...”
"My eyes are heavy..."
“我的心很沉重... ...”
"My heart is heavy..."
“你破坏了我的信仰”
"You broke my faith."
“我们在一起”
"We were together."
“你的意图是什么?”
"What was your intention?"
“亲爱的，你这是怎么了?”
"What strange way of yours is this, dear?"
“亲爱的，你为什么要和我分手?”
"Why did you break up with me, dear?"
“你的爱是什么样的，亲爱的?”
"What kind of love is yours, dear?"
“我曾是你的爱人，现在我什么都不是了”
"I was your love sometime back and now I am nothing."
这是什么地方？
Where have we come?
你马上就知道了 -嘿，格里？
You will come to know. - Hey Guri?
这是谁的房子？
Whose house is this?
你坐好
You keep sitting.
我要见阿比拉什
I want to meet Abhilash.
谁是阿比拉什？
Who Abhilash?
阿比拉什 · 夏尔马，IAS，我要见他
Abhilash Sharma, IAS. I want to meet him.
先生，这是官员的房子
Sir, this is the house of an IAS officer.
没有预约，你不能见他
You cannot meet him without an appointment.
我是他的朋友，你叫他出来
I am his friend. Call him.
也许你是他的朋友
Maybe you are his friend.
我告诉你
I am telling you that
别大喊大叫
Don't shout.
- 给他打电话-小声点
- Call him up. - Talk softly.
-你去旁边站着
- - You go and stand there quietly.
请打电话给他
Please call him.
你别喊
Stop screaming first.
我请你打电话给他，他是我的朋友
I am asking you to call him. He is my friend.
- 小声点，不然我就开枪了-你要开枪吗？
- Talk softly or I will shoot. - Will you shoot me?
让我看看你是怎么杀我的
Let me see how you shoot me.
打电话告诉他我们来了
Just call him and tell him that we have come.
退后，快点
Get back. Come on.
先生
Sir.
长官，外面有两个人在打架
Sir, two people are fighting outside.
他们说他们是你的朋友
They say that they are your friends.
他们想见你
They want to meet you.
你没受过教育吗？
Are you uneducated?
他本来可以打你的，他是个警察
He could have hit you. He is a policeman.
别咄咄逼人，明白吗？
Don't get aggressive. Understood?
- 胡说-让他们进来
- Nonsense. - Let them in.
嗨，阿比拉什
Hi, Abhilash.
你在这儿等着
You wait here. You are not needed today.
你没通知我们就走了
You left without informing us.
发生了紧急情况
An emergency has come up.
我得去兰普尔了
I have to leave for Rampur.
对不起，我没通知你就走了
Sorry. I left without informing you.
你要马上离开吗？
Are you leaving immediately?
是的，汽车10分钟后到
Yes. The car would arrive in 10 minutes.
要喝点什么吗？
Will you have a drink?
不
No.
放下吧
Let it be.
既然你要走了，我们再喝最后一杯吧
Let's drink for one last time. Now that you are leaving.
我去弄点喝的
I will make a drink.
你不用带行李就走吗？
Are you leaving without taking your belongings?
干杯
Cheers.
怎么？
So?
你一定有很多女朋友
You must be having many girlfriends.
现在你在和谁约会？
Whom are you dating nowadays?
没有人
No one.
为什么? 你们分手了？
Why? Did you break up?
是的
Yes.
她妨碍你履行职责了吗？
Did she come in between you and your duty?
你在说什么，格里？
What are you talking, Guri?
别越线
Stay in your limits.
你说得对，只有官员先生才有地位
You are right. Only Mr. Collector has a position.
而不是像我们这样的人
And not people like us.
你是不是在报复
Are you taking revenge for the
发生在我们之间的问题，格里？
problem that happened between us, Guri?
是这样吗？
Isn't it?
你一点都不觉得内疚吗？
You do not have even slight guilt?
你想怎样，阿比拉什？
What do you want, Abhilash?
你不想让我结婚吗？
Don't you want me to get married?
告诉我
Tell me.
你要和你朋友的女朋友结婚了
You are marrying the girlfriend of your friend.
哪个女朋友？
Which girlfriend?
你知道过去6年她在哪儿吗？
Do you have an idea where she is for the last 6 years?
女朋友
Girlfriend.
你知道吗
You know
我曾经觉得自己做的不对
I was guilty earlier
这就是为什么我没有告诉 SK
and that is why I did not tell SK about this.
当我告诉他时... 他对你很有信心
And when I told him... he had faith in you.
所以我才鼓起勇气告诉了你
That is why I gathered courage to tell you.
你从餐厅离开的时候我就意识到了
I realized it when you left from there.
我犯了什么错，兄弟？
What is my mistake, buddy?
告诉我，我错在哪里？
Tell me what is my mistake?
你想让我感到内疚
You want me to feel guilty.
我完全没有做错任何事
I am not at all guilty.
我无罪
I am not guilty.
你必须接受这个事实
You will have to accept this.
让我们忘记发生的一切
Let us forget all that happened between us.
我想让你参加我的婚礼
I want you to attend my marriage.
格里，不管你在做什么都是错的
Guri, whatever you are doing is wrong.
你现在做的事一文不值
You are doing a cheap thing.
这意味着你不能参加我的婚礼
That means you will not attend my wedding.
不能
No.
那好吧
Okay then.
你一定没有意识到这一点
You must not have ever realized it
你一直在假装积极的态度
but all this while you were faking about the positive approach.
你可能通过了考试，成为了一名公务员
You may have cleared the exam and have become an officer
但你之前的生活方式是错误的
but your approach towards life was wrong earlier
现在也是
and even now.
我走了
I'll leave.
好久不见，海莉娅。我知道已经过去六年了，你最近过得怎么样？
不眠之夜，心情沉重
'Restless nights. Heavy heart.'
睁开眼睛
'Open eyes...'
“每个人都疯了”
'There is madness in everyone.'
负重的心灵中的这些小小的梦想开始成长
'These small dreams in burdened minds dare to grow.'
黑暗房间里的一缕阳光
'A ray of sunlight In dark rooms'
点燃希望，然后离开
'ignite hope and leaves.'
潮湿的气味提醒你
'The smell of dampness reminds you'
没有你认识的人
'that there is no one you know.'
只有孤独
'There is only loneliness.'
梦想，阳光，气味
'Dreams, sunlight, smell.'
“这是一种相互联系的疯狂”
'This is madness that connects with each other.'
我们不累，我们没有停下来
'We are not tired, we have not stopped.'
“我们还没有变得毫无生气”
'We have not become lifeless yet.'
因为每个人都有疯狂的一面
'Because there is madness in everyone.'
让开
Move aside.
（两个月后）
佩玛，起来，结果出来了
Pema, get up. The result is out.
我没去考试
I did not give the exam.
让我看看
Let me check.
请让开
Please move aside.
帮我看一下我的成绩
Please check my result.
请稍微让一下
Please move a little bit.
给我个位置
Give me the way.
请让我查一下
Please let me check.
-太棒了，我通过了-你通过了吗？
- Yes, I cleared. - Did you clear?
- 你也通过了吗?-是的
- Did you clear too? - Yes, I did.
我找不到我的号码，帮我看一下
I am not able to find out my roll number. Please check.
你能看到吗？
Are you able to see it?
不，我没看到
No. I am not.
“这些记忆仍然鲜活”
"These memories are still fresh."
“这些记忆仍然在我心中”
"These memories are still in me."
“不要离开视线，我的朋友”
"Do not get out of sight, my friend."
“不要像一朵云一样匆匆而过”
"Don't just pass by like a cloud."
“这条连接线永远不能断开”
"This thread of connection should never break."
”这许多回忆的线索”
"This thread of many memories"
“这根线永远不会断... ...”
"This thread should never break..."
“这条微妙的承诺之线”
"This thread of delicate promises."
“我受伤的时候你修补过吗?”
"Did you mend it when I was broken?"
“是你造就了我”
"You had made me."
”当你的东西变成了我的”
"When what was yours became mine"
“没有你，我觉得不完整”
"It felt incomplete without you."
“因为你，我的世界才完整”
"My world was complete because of you."
“我是很晚才知道的”
"I came to know this very late."